Guide to the John R. Hamburg Transportation Papers, 1956-1992
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: The John R. Hamburg Transportation Papers, April 1956-April 1992
  - Determination of Origin-Destination Matrices from Link Volumes and Turning Movements, February 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Responses to questions about a proposal from John Hamburg and Associates called Determination of Origin-Destination Matrices from Link Volumes and Turning Movements.
  - Miscellaneous, November 1976-June 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Material in this file includes a cost proposal called Determination of Origin-Destination Matrices from Link-Volume and Turning Movement Data, correspondence, lists of previously completed contracts, budget information, a handwritten letter, graphs and notes.
  - Miscellaneous, March 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    A rough draft of a letter from John Hamburg,"The Use of Equilibrium Assignment Techniques", "Comments Regarding the Use of a Network Equilibrium Model When Determining OD Movements from Observed Link Flows and Turning Movements", pricing information and notes.
  - Theory of Transportation and Land Development, May 1969-June 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    A rough draft and final copy of "Theory of Transportation and Land Development - Program Documentation".
  - Adaptation and Calibration of Micro Assignment to the Golden Triangle Area of Pittsburgh, February 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    The final report on a contract between Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission and Creighton, Hamburg Incorporated.
  - Micro Assignment Final Report Volume II - Program Documentation, October 1969-December 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    The final report prepared for the US Department of Transportation Federal Highway Administration on a model created to show traffic patterns. See folder 4.8 for volume 1.
  - Memo on Highway Capacity, January 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    A memo that discusses the impact of capacity in the simulation process, reviews some of the alternatives for obtaining capacity, and recommends how capacities should be inserted into the 1960 Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission network.
  - Final Report to North Central Texas Council of Governments, February-July 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    The final report to the North Central Texas Council of Governments Regional Travel Survey Volume 1 Home Interview Surveys.
  - Preliminary Results of Trip Generation Analysis, August 1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    A memo describing investigation and analysis of the trip generation model implemented in a computer program.
  - Thoroughfare Planning System, Thoroughfare Information System, November 1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Technical specifications and user documentation of Program CAPSPD for a thoroughfare planning system and a thoroughfare information system.
  - NCTCOG Model System Description, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    An overview description of the North Central Texas Council of Governments Multimodal Transportation Analysis Process.
  - Proposal to Conduct a Travel Demand Study for the PIMA Association of Governments, February 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Proposed Methodology for Drawing a Sample of Buses, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    A paper describing the proposed methodology for drawing a sample of buses for the 1977 Revenue Allocation Project.
  - Sampling Variability and Recommended Procedures for Estimating Sample Precision, November 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    A memo from John Hamburg addressing the issue of sampling variability and procedures for calculating the precision of the estimates of revenue by jurisdiction for the bus survey.
  - Proposal for the Administration of a Transit Impact Monitoring Program Workplace Survey, April 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    A proposal for a study which would obtain statistically valid information on the travel characteristics of the work or school trips of employees or students working or attending school in areas well-served by the Metropolitan Atlanta Rapid Transit Authority Phase A rail system.
  - Use of the Thoroughfare Planning System, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    A large document about the use of the thoroughfare planning system.
  - Integrating Transportation Systems Management Into the Overall Transportation Planning Process, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    A document by John Hamburg and George Lathrop titled "Integrating TSM into the Overall Transportation Planning Process".
  - Average Vehicle Ridership Calculation, September 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and a copy of the AVR calculation worksheet.
  - Local Rail Freight Assistance Program, July 1990-March 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Two documents about the Local Rail Freight Assistance Program, a benefit-cost methodology from the Federal Railroad Administration and the 1991 New Mexico State Rail Plan Update appendix on applying the benefit-cost methodology.
  - New Mexico Project, February 1990-March 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Documents and correspondence about a proposed project in New Mexico. Material includes notes, "A Strategic Plan for Measuring and Forecasting Multimodal Transportation Activity" by Rolf R. Schmitt, "Highway Traffic Forecasting System Overview" by Rolf R. Schmitt, an introduction to Large Scale Simulation, cost estimates for taking household surveys of travel habits, evaluations of proposals, a scope of services for the project "Commodity Flows Within a Multimodal Transportation Forecast Model", "Initial reflections on Multimodal Large Scale Simulation Initiatives" by John Hamburg, budget information and comments on "Commodity Shipments Within a Multimodal Transportation Forecast Model" Proposal.
  - AMTECH Corporation, April 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    A video tape from AMTECH Corporation titled "Welcome to the Future".
  - Chicago Area Transportation Study, April 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Volume one of a coding manual for the Chicago Area Transportation Study.
  - Miscellaneous, April 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Miscellaneous files including an incomplete memo, a packet of maps, workshop minutes and attendance lists.